←@
♪MINUTES OF THE FIRST BOARD MEETING OF KAPIS CREDITS AND LEASING PRIVATE LIMITED♪◙
HELD ON WEDNESDAY,THE 05th OCTOBER 1994AT 400, OLD ANAJ MANDI, HISAR – 125001, AT 4.00 PM.♪◙

DIRECTORS PRESENT:
	
Mr. Vikram Garg		
Mr. Bhagwat Saroop Garg					

Item no. 1 - CHAIRMAN OF THE MEETING

Mr. Vikram Gargwas appointed as Chairman of the meeting. Accordingly, Mr. Vikram Garg took the Chair and conducted the proceedings of the meeting.
Item no. 2 - QUORUM

The chairman having ascertained the quorum, called the meeting to order.

Item no. 3 - LEAVE OF ABSENCE

All the directors were present.

Item no. 4 - CERTIFICATE OF INCORPORATION OF THE COMPANY

The Certificate of Incorporation No. 05-32398dated 13th September 1994 issued by the Registrar of Companies, NCT of Delhi and Haryana, incorporating the Company with effect from 13th September 1994along with the copies of the Memorandum and Articles of Association of the Company, was placed on the table of the meeting and was noted by the Board.

Item no. 5 - CONSTITUTION OF THE BOARD – FIRST DIRECTORS OF THE COMPANY

The Chairman informed the Board that the following persons in pursuance of Article 17 of the Articles of Association pertaining to determination of the first Directors of the Company, constitute the first Board of Directors of the Company:
Mr. Vikram Garg		-     Director
Mr. Bhagwat Saroop Garg	-     Director

Item no. 6 - SUBSCRIBERS TO THE MEMORANDUM OF ASSOCIATION

A copy of the Memorandum and Articles of Association was placed on the table. The Board noted that the following persons have subscribed to the memorandum and have subscribed to the Equity Shares as mentioned against their names.

As the Company had received payment in full in respect of equity shares taken by the subscribers to the Memorandum of Association of the Company, it is:

“RESOLVED THAT the subscribers to the Memorandum of Association having agreed to take and having made the payment be and are hereby allotted equity shares of the Company, the details whereof are mentioned below:

S.NoFolio no.Name of subscriber No. of shares   Distinctive numbers  Face value per share  Amount   Certificate no.  From  To 11Bhagwat Saroop Garg                   100                            1                        100 10             1,000 122Vikram Garg                   100                        101                        200 10             1,000 2
RESOLVED FURTHER THAT the Share Certificates shall be signed by Mr. Vikram Garg, Director and Mr. Bhagwat Saroop Garg, and the common seal be affixed thereon in their presence. 

Item no. 7 - SITUATION OF REGISTERED OFFICE OF THE COMPANY

The Chairman informed the Board that the Company’s Registered Office is situated at 400, Old AnajMandi Road, Hisar-125001and the information regarding location of the Registered Office of the Company in the prescribed form has already been filed with the Registrar of Companies, NCT of Delhi & Haryana. The Board took note of the same and passed the following resolution in this regard.
“RESOLVED THAT a name plate or board be affixed at the Registered Office and that the Company’s name & address of the Registered Office be used or mentioned in legible characters in all business letters, bill heads and letter papers and all its notices and other official publications etc., pursuant to Sec 147 of the Companies Act, 1956.”

Item no. 8 - FINANCIAL YEAR OF THE COMPANY

The Chairman proposed that the first financial year of the Company be from the date of incorporation of the Company i.e. September13, 1994 to March 31, 1995. The subsequent financial years be from April 01 to March 31 of each year. The Board discussed and passed the following resolution in this regard:
“RESOLVED THAT the first Financial Year of the Company be the period from the date of incorporation of the Company i.e. September 13,1994 to March 31,1995, both days inclusive, and that the second and subsequent financial years of the Company be the period from April 01 to March 31, in each year.”

Item no. 9 - ADOPTION OF COMMON SEAL

The Chairman placed on the table of the meeting, the engraved common seal for adoption by the Board. The following resolution was passed:
“RESOLVED THAT the Common Seal as per impression affixed in the margin of the minutes, initialed by the Chairman, and produced at the meeting be and is hereby approved and adopted as the common seal of the Company and that the Common Seal shall be kept in the safe custody of Mr. Vikram Garg, Director.”


IMPRESSION OF COMMON SEAL





Item no. 10 - GENERAL NOTICE OF DISCLOSURE OF INTEREST U/S 299 OF THE COMPANIES ACT, 1956

The general notice of disclosure of interest received from Directors of the Company pursuant to Section 299 of the Companies Act, 1956 were placed on the table of the meeting. The Board took note of the same and the same to be recorded in the statutory register to be maintained pursuant to Section 301 of the Companies Act, 1956.
Item no. 11 - PRINTING OF SHARE CERTIFICATES

A specimen of the Share Certificate was placed before the Board. The same was approved by the Board and the following resolution was passed:
“RESOLVED THAT the Share certificates be printed as per the specimen submitted to this meeting and they be consecutively numbered and that the forms and blocks, designs etc., relating to the printing of such share certificates be kept in safe custody of Mr. Vikram Garg, Director.

Item no. 12 - PROCEDURE OF RECORDING MINUTES OF BOARD MEETING AND GENERAL MEETINGS 

The Board approved the procedure laid down under Section 193 of the Companies Act, 1956, for recording the minutes of the meeting of the Board of directors and those of members being followed. It was also decided that the minutes be kept in a bound loose-leaf minutes book duly typed, stitched, serially numbered and initialed by the Chairman of the meeting and every such bound loose leaf minutes book be bound after a certain period of time, as may be decided by the Chairman.
Item no. 13 - MAINTENANCE OF STATUTORY REGISTERS
Mr. Vikram Garg, Director of the Company was authorized to do all such acts, deeds and things for the maintenance of all the Statutory Registers required under the Companies Act, 1956 and to make necessary entries therein.
Item no. 14 - OPENING AND OPERATION OF BANK ACCOUNT
It was suggested that a current banking account be opened in the name of Kapis Credits and Leasing Private Limited with Punjab National Bank in Hisar and elsewhere in the country, Mr. Vikram Garg, Director be authorised to operate the same.  In this connection the following resolution was passed:

“RESOLVED THAT the banking account or accounts be opened with Punjab National Bank.

That the bank be instructed to pay and honour all cheques or other order expressed to be drawn on behalf of the Company and to accept and act upon any instructions relating to the account or accounts kept in the name of the Company or relating to any transactions of the Company with the bank, provided the cheques, orders or instructions are signed by Mr.Vikram Garg or Mr. Bhagwat Saroop Garg, Director for the time being of the company.

That the Bank be instructed to honor all bills accepted and promissory notes made on behalf of the Company payable at the said Bank at any time or times provided such bills or notes are signed by Mr. Vikram Garg or Mr. Bhagwat Saroop Garg, Director for the time being of the Company.

That with regard to all negotiable instruments or documents relation to goods paid into the account for collection or discounted or negotiated with the bank expressed to the endorsed on behalf of the Company, the said bank be instructed to treat such instruments and documents as having being duly endorsed on behalf of the Company provided they are signed by Mr. Vikram Garg or Mr. Bhagwat Saroop Garg, Directors for the time being of the Company.

That the said bank be instructed to accept the receipts for any monies, deeds, securities or other documents or papers or property and any indemnities given on behalf of the Company provided they are signed by Mr. Vikram Garg or Mr. Bhagwat Saroop Garg, Directors for the time being of the Company.

That the bank be furnished with a list of the names of the directors of the Company and a copy of its Memorandum and Articles of Association and be from time to time informed by notice in writing under the hand of the Chairman of any changes which may take place therein and be entitled to act upon any such notice until the receipt of further notice under the hand of the Chairman.

That these resolutions be communicated to the Bank and remain in force until duly rescinded and notice thereof in writing be given to the Bank by the Chairman of the Company.

Item no. 15 - APPLICATION TO DEPARTMENT OF INCOME TAX FOR OBTAINING PERMANENT ACCOUNT NUMBER (PAN)

“RESOLVED THAT approval be and is hereby granted to make application to the Department of Income Tax for allotment of Permanent Account Number (PAN) u/s 139A of The Income Tax Act.”

The Director, Mr. Vikram Garg is hereby severally authorized to sign the application, undertaking, affidavit, declaration, and all other documents and  to do all such acts, deeds and things, which may be necessary to obtain the PAN.

Item no. 16 - APPLICATION TO DEPARTMENT OF INCOME TAX FOR OBTAINING TAX DEDUCTION AND COLLECTION ACCOUNT NUMBER (TAN)

“RESOLVED THAT approval be and is hereby granted to make application to the Department of Income Tax for allotment of Tax Deduction and Collection Account Number (TAN) u/s 203A of The Income Tax Act, 1961.”
The Director, Mr. Vikram Garg is hereby severally authorized to sign the application, undertaking, affidavit, declaration, and all other documents and  to do all such acts, deeds and things, which may be necessary to obtain the TAN.




Item no. 17 - APPOINTMENT OF FIRST AUDITORS

The Chairman informed the Board that S.C Thakral& Co., Chartered Accountants, have offered themselves to act as first auditors of the Company and who are not disqualified to act, within the provisions of Companies Act, 1956. Accordingly the following resolution was unanimously passed:

“RESOLVED THATpursuant to Sec 224(5) of the Companies Act, 1956, subject to the approval of shareholders, S.C Thakral& Co. who have offered themselves for the appointment and who are not disqualified to act, within the provisions of Companies Act, 1956, be and hereby are appointed as auditors of the Company to hold office from the date of its incorporation until the conclusion of its first Annual General Meeting of the Company and for remuneration to be decided by the Board.”

VOTE OF THANKS 

There being no other business the meeting came to an end with a vote of thanks to the chair.
 



Date:
Place:Hisar

                                                                                                                                Chairman
 (Vikram Garg)


MINUTES OF THE BOARD MEETING OF KAPIS CREDITS AND LEASING PRIVATE LIMITED HELD ON WEDNESDAY,THE 31stMARCH 1995AT 400, OLD ANAJ MANDI, HISAR – 125001, AT 4.00 PM.

DIRECTORS PRESENT:
	
Mr. Vikram Garg		
Mr. Bhagwat Saroop Garg	

Item no. 1 - CHAIRMAN OF THE MEETING

Mr. Vikram Garg was appointed as Chairman of the meeting. Accordingly, Mr. Vikram Garg took the Chair and conducted the proceedings of the meeting.
Item no. 2 - QUORUM

The chairman having ascertained the quorum, called the meeting to order.

Item no. 3 - LEAVE OF ABSENCE

All the directors were present.

Item no. 4 –ISSUE OF EQUITY SHARES OF THE COMPANY

“RESOLVEDTHAT according to the Article of Association of the company, shareholders as listed below be and are hereby allotted and issued equity shares each having a nominal value of Rs. 10/-(Rupees 10 only) in lieu of subscription monies received from them approved by the board as per the details given below:


S.NoFolio no.Name of subscriber No. of shares   Distinctive numbers 

From To  Face value per share  Amount   Certificate no. 11Bhagwat Saroop Garg              18,400                        201                   18,600 10        1,84,000                        3 22Vikram Garg                7,900                   18,601                   26,500 10           79,000                        4 33Jinender Jain                3,500                   26,501                   30,000 10           35,000                        5 44Ram Bilas Aggarwal                   500                   30,001                   30,500 10             5,000                        6 55Veena Bansal                   500                   30,501                   31,000 10             5,000                        7 66Suresh Garg              10,000                   31,001                   41,000 10        1,00,000                        8 77Krishna Garg              23,000                   41,001                   64,000 10        2,30,000                        9 88Bhagwat Saroop Garg HUF              16,000                   64,001                   80,000 10        1,60,000                      10 99Seeta Garg                   100                   80,001                   80,100 10             1,000                      11 1010Yashica Garg                1,000                   80,101                   81,100 10           10,000                      12 1111Sunita Garg                7,500                   81,101                   88,600 10           75,000                      13 1212Gaurav Garg                1,000                   88,601                   89,600 10           10,000                      14 1313Sheela Thakral              13,000                   89,601                1,02,600 10        1,30,000                      15 1414Krishan Kumar Thakral                7,500                1,02,601                1,10,100 10           75,000                      16 1515Savita Thakral              11,000                1,10,101                1,21,100 10        1,10,000                      17 1616VedParkashBindal                9,000                1,21,101                1,30,100 10           90,000                      18 1717Krishan Goyal                8,000                1,30,101                1,38,100 10           80,000                      19 1818Ajay Goyal                8,000                1,38,101                1,46,100 10           80,000                      20 1919Sajan Goyal                5,000                1,46,101                1,51,100 10           50,000                      21 2020Jagmohan Garg                   100                1,51,101                1,51,200 10             1,000                      22 2121Sandeep Arya                   100                1,51,201                1,51,300 10             1,000                      23 2222Mahesh Jain                   100                1,51,301                1,51,400 10             1,000                      24 2323Devi Dutt Sharma                   100                1,51,401                1,51,500 10             1,000                      25 2424Geeta Jain                   100                1,51,501                1,51,600 10             1,000                      26 2525Kamlesh Jain                   100                1,51,601                1,51,700 10             1,000                      27 2626Shashi Jain                   100                1,51,701                1,51,800 10             1,000                      28 2727Parimal Singh Chaudhary                100                1,51,801                1,51,900                          10              1,000                      29 2828Babul Singh Chaudhary                   100                1,51,901                1,52,000                          10              1,000                      30 2929Rakesh Sharma                   100                1,52,001                1,52,100                          10              1,000                      31 3030Naval Kishore                   100                1,52,101                1,52,200                          10              1,000                      32 3131Rajender Verma                   100                1,52,201                1,52,300                          10              1,000                      33 3232Dinesh Mangal                   100                1,52,301                1,52,400                          10              1,000                      34 3333Brij Mohan Garg                   100                1,52,401                1,52,500                          10              1,000                      35 3434SatpalCharaya              10,000                1,52,501                1,62,500                          10         1,00,000                      36 3535Surjeet Singh                   400                1,62,501                1,62,900                          10              4,000                      37 3635Surjeet Singh                   400                1,62,901                1,63,300                          10              4,000                      38 3735Surjeet Singh                   400                1,63,301                1,63,700                          10              4,000                      39 3835Surjeet Singh                   100                1,63,701                1,63,800                          10              1,000                      40 3935Surjeet Singh                   100                1,63,801                1,63,900                          10              1,000                      41 4035Surjeet Singh                   100                1,63,901                1,64,000                          10              1,000                      42 4135Surjeet Singh                   100                1,64,001                1,64,100                          10              1,000                      43 4235Surjeet Singh                   100                1,64,101                1,64,200                          10              1,000                      44 4335Surjeet Singh                   100                1,64,201                1,64,300                          10              1,000                      45 4435Surjeet Singh                   100                1,64,301                1,64,400                          10              1,000                      46 4535Surjeet Singh                   100                1,64,401                1,64,500                          10              1,000                      47 4635Surjeet Singh                   100                1,64,501                1,64,600                          10              1,000                      48 4735Surjeet Singh                1,000                1,64,601                1,65,600                          10            10,000                      49 4835Surjeet Singh                   900                1,65,601                1,66,500                          10              9,000                      50 4935Surjeet Singh                2,500                1,66,501                1,69,000                          10            25,000                      51 



RESOLVED FURTHER THAT the above equity shares so issued and allotted to the respective subscribers in accordance with the provisions of the Memorandum and Articles of Association of the Company. 

RESOLVED FURTHER THAT the company issued the letter of allotment in relation to the aforesaid equity shares allotted in the name of the shareholder. 

RESOLVED FURTHER THAT to make the above resolution effective, the Mr. Vikram Gargis authorized to do all acts, deeds and things, including issuance of duly stamped share certificates in relation to the above equity shares issued and allotted as aforesaid to respective shareholders under the provisions of the Companies Act, 1956 and rules made there under and the Articles of Association of the Company. Mr. Vikram Garg can do all other acts in accordance with the issuance and allotment, including, in particular the payment of the requisite stamp duty, for issuing duly stamped share certificates evidencing the allotment of equity shares and give such directions as may be required, necessary, expedient or desirable for giving effect to the aforesaid resolutions.”

Item no. 5- REVIEW OF THE OPERATIONS OF THE COMPANY

The Board reviewed the Company’s operations, industry overview, strategy and growth plans and achievements of the Company.

VOTE OF THANKS 

There being no other business the meeting came to an end with a vote of thanks to the chair.
 



Date: 
Place: Hisar

                                                                                                                                Chairman
                                                                                                                                     (Vikram Garg)


				



	

